<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arturo Freydig Avila</title>
    <link>https://arturofa95.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Arturo Freydig Avila</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 22:12:57 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://arturofa95.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://arturofa95.github.io/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 22:12:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arturofa95.github.io/about-me/</guid>
      <description>I am currently an M.S. Electrical Engineering student at the University of Colorado Boulder, I am focusing my coursework and research in Control Systems and Artificial Intelligence (AI). I have a B.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering, Applied Mathematics, and Mechanical Engineering from the University of Colorado Boulder. In addition to my degrees, I also obtained certificates in Engineering Leadership and Global Engineering.
My research interests are in: hybrid dynamical systems, applied machine learning, optimization, statistics, autonomy, and social engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Blog</title>
      <link>https://arturofa95.github.io/posts/my_first_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 22:00:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arturofa95.github.io/posts/my_first_blog/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone, I will start writing blogs on the subjects of: Hybrid Dynamical Control, Machine Learning, Control Systems, Electronics, DIY, Optimization, Mathematics, Automation, and Autonomous Vehicles. I hope these posts will be useful to people interested in these fields and will provide rich and relevant content. I will likely also post these in Medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Projects</title>
      <link>https://arturofa95.github.io/projects/selected_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 22:00:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arturofa95.github.io/projects/selected_projects/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this post is to highlight most of the projects I have done as a graduate/undergraduate student, intern, and hobbyist. I will explain in more detail the projects listed here in different posts.
Machine Learning ML) / Artificial Intelligence (AI) Projects  Obstacle Avoidance Navigation using Radial Basis Network (one and two layers) COVID-19 X-Ray Based Detection using a Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) COVID-19 Case Prediction using a Recurrent Neural Network (RNN), Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM), and a Gated Recurrent Unit (GRU) Neural Ordinary Differential Equations (ODE) Survey Notebook Atari Paper Overview Notebook PyTorch vs Keras Notebook CNN to detect Birds using Wi-Fi Long Distance and a Raspberry Pi Using a CNN to detect the work yes and light and LED in a microcontroller (TinyML) Tarea de Data  Control Systems Projects  Obstacle Avoidance Navigation using Classic Averaging and Perturbation Theory and Hybrid Control based on Point-Mass and Nonholonomic Dynamics Inverted Pendulum Control using a PID and an LQR Controller 1-D Vehicle Control Simulation using Digital Control  Electrical/Electronics  Wireless Glove Vehicle Controller Softrobot Capable of Grabbing Light-weight Cans LED PCB Board Sensor projects Various ESP32, Arduino, and Raspberry Pi projects FPGA Projects Software Define Radio (SDR) Emotion Detection Door handle based on phone movement Solar Microgrid with LiFePO4 Batteries  Mechanical Projects  Mechanical Drill Vehicle CAD Helicopter Design Double Steam Design (Thermo) Algo con manufacturing Gravity-based Lamp Structure for lld  Software projects  C++ FPGA Interface and Bit Reader (intern project) Python-based GUI for Controller (intern project) MATLAB Control Systems Toolbox Examples C++ Data Structure&amp;rsquo;s Examples  StartUp Projects  LiFePO4 Battery Design and Supplier StartUp (Failed due to political issues in Bolivia) StartUp Stock Market (Failed due to different interests from founders)  Others  St.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>